Hip sort is one algorithm used to sort a sequence of numbers and features the use of the hip data structure
to begin all of these numbers five two, seven, three, six, one and four hour sorted in a heap.
These hips are constructed so that numbers in are in descending order.
A more detailed explanation of hip can be found in the hips.
Previous videos.
So.
To begin all of these numbers.
Are sorted in a heap.
As I told you, we start by the first one.
We start making it into a heap, so please go back to the previous pages about the heap data structure
and learn about the heap in order to continue understanding the heap.
And we put five and connected with two.
Five and seven seven is greater than five, so we put it in there as per.
We continue getting three.
Three is greater than two.
So we scrap them because we are hip defying six.
Is greater than three.
So we switch three by six.
Remember, these hips are constructed so that the numbers are in descending order because we learned
that the hips.
The president has the minimum number and the minimum and the lowest number, then the children.
OK, lower number and then the children, because this is an ascending order in descending order that
parents have their greatest elements, their greatest values and their children have the less.
OK, now we get one.
We add number four.
Four is less than five, so it will add it completely to that child as if children are five, so that
children is less than that permanence in all the levels of this heap because we are making and constructing
this hips constructed in a. descending order.
So we have we have succeeded in adding these elements into their descending order.
OK, so all the numbers have been sorted in a heap.
Next, the numbers stored in the heap are taken out one by one.
One property of descending hips is that the numbers are removed from the largest to smallest.
So if the if you line the numbers up in the opposite order right to left as they get remove sorting
is complete.
How that is done.
So seven is removed.
We swept the six with four and then.
We remove six.
Five is going up.
Five will be removed so that three would go up and four will be swept, the five if we move forward.
Two will go up and three will go up.
So three will be that president.
Three will be here and still having to end on right to left and one is at it.
So all the numbers were removed from the heap and the sorting is completed while we prepared an extra
data structure apart from the sequence number this time.
Normally, the heap is incorporated into the very array containing the sequence of numbers and sorting
is carried out by simply swapping the numbers around to give more concrete example.
The elements of the heap nodes and the array.
Have a corresponding relationship, as shown in the dig, a b, c, d, e f and G, F and G.
Okay.
Related to C so b related to the NDA and C it related to F and edgy.
As you can see, it could be said that the hip is just crammed into an attorney.
Now let's try sorting the array using this wrapping method.
The hip to make things easier to understand.
We will keep that three structure of the hip visible.
Five.
Two, seven, seven is changed.
Here we are swapping in three, swapping six, swapping four.
And till now, it is good.
No, let's start.
All numbers have been sorted in the heap.
At the same time, we are able to arrange that array in descending order at the hit.
Next, the numbers sorted in the heap are taken out one by one descending order hips have their data
removed in order starting from the largest values, the first number, and that is the largest number
in the heap.
The first number in the array gets swept with that number that corresponds to that last element is a
heap and completing the operation.
The hip is reorganized so that it has its data structure is maintained.
This operation repeats until of all numbers have been fully sorted.
Sorting is completed, and this is their conclusion of the absurd.
Now let's try to and let's move to that next.
Lessons to learn about its complexity and how this heap sort works.
Also in details and let's try to implement it and see and.